[
  {
    "question": "Which operation can be performed between two string variables?",
    "a": "Multiplication",
    "b": "Concatenation",
    "c": "Division",
    "d": "Subtraction",
    "answer": "Concatenation"
  },
  {
    "question": "What logical operator is used to reverse the result of a condition?",
    "a": "and",
    "b": "or",
    "c": "not",
    "d": "xor",
    "answer": "not"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will the pop() method return if used on the list [1, 'hello', 3.14] without specifying an index?",
    "a": 1,
    "b": "[]",
    "c": 3.14,
    "d": "'hello'",
    "answer": 3.14
  },
  {
    "question": "In a for loop, what does the range(1, 10, 2) function call do?",
    "a": "Iterates from 1 to 9, excluding 10, with steps of 2",
    "b": "Iterates from 1 to 10, including 10, with steps of 2",
    "c": "Iterates from 1 to 9, including 10, in reverse with steps of 2",
    "d": "Iterates from 1 to 10, excluding 10, in reverse with steps of 2",
    "answer": "Iterates from 1 to 9, excluding 10, with steps of 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which function is used to parse a JSON string back into a Python dictionary?",
    "a": "json.loads()",
    "b": "json.parse()",
    "c": "json.get()",
    "d": "json.dump()",
    "answer": "json.loads()"
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you write \"Python is fun!\" to a new file named newfile.txt?\n\nwith open('newfile.txt', 'w') as file:\n  file.write(\"Python is fun!\")",
    "a": "The code will throw an error because the file does not exist.",
    "b": "The code will create newfile.txt and write \"Python is fun!\" to it.",
    "c": "The code will append \"Python is fun!\" to newfile.txt without creating a new file.",
    "d": "The code will read \"Python is fun!\" from newfile.txt.",
    "answer": "The code will create newfile.txt and write \"Python is fun!\" to it."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does len(\"Hello World\") return?",
    "a": "11",
    "b": "SyntaxError",
    "c": "10",
    "d": "12",
    "answer": "11"
  },
  {
    "question": "For a leap year program, which combination of conditions would be accurate?",
    "a": "year % 4 == 0 or year % 100 != 0 and year % 400 == 0",
    "b": "year % 4 == 0 and year % 100 != 0 or year % 400 == 0",
    "c": "year % 4 != 0 and year % 100 == 0 or year % 400 != 0",
    "d": "year % 4 == 0 and (year % 100 != 0 or year % 400 == 0)",
    "answer": "year % 4 == 0 and (year % 100 != 0 or year % 400 == 0)"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will be the output of the following Python code?\n\nsum = 10.5 + 2.5\nprint(sum)",
    "a": "12",
    "b": "13",
    "c": "13.0",
    "d": "TypeError",
    "answer": "13.0"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of variables in Python?",
    "a": "To perform complex mathematical operations",
    "b": "To control the flow of a program",
    "c": "To act as containers to store data values",
    "d": "To define functions and methods",
    "answer": "To act as containers to store data values"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the following dictionary comprehension output?\n\n{x: x**2 for x in range(5)}",
    "a": "{0: 0, 1: 1, 2: 4, 3: 9, 4: 16}",
    "b": "[0, 1, 4, 9, 16]",
    "c": "TypeError",
    "d": "None",
    "answer": "{0: 0, 1: 1, 2: 4, 3: 9, 4: 16}"
  },
  {
    "question": "Considering Python's operator precedence, what is the result of the expression 3 + 2 * 2 ?",
    "a": "10",
    "b": "7",
    "c": "12",
    "d": "5",
    "answer": "7"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which method is used to insert an element at a specific index in a list?",
    "a": "add()",
    "b": "push()",
    "c": "insert()",
    "d": "place()",
    "answer": "insert()"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do you convert a Python dictionary to a JSON string?",
    "a": "Using json.dumps()",
    "b": "Using json.stringify()",
    "c": "Using json.parse()",
    "d": "Using json.loads()",
    "answer": "Using json.dumps()"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nested conditional statements are used for:",
    "a": "Simplifying complex conditions into a single line",
    "b": "Hierarchical decision-making",
    "c": "Executing the same code block multiple times",
    "d": "Avoiding the use of logical operators",
    "answer": "Hierarchical decision-making"
  },
  {
    "question": "How do you ensure a `while` loop is executed at least once regardless of the condition",
    "a": "By using a do-while loop",
    "b": "By setting the condition to True initially",
    "c": "By writing the loop's code block before the while statement",
    "d": "By using a for loop instead",
    "answer": "By setting the condition to True initially"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mode allows you to append content to an existing file without overwriting it?",
    "a": "'a'",
    "b": "'r+'",
    "c": "'x'",
    "d": "'w+'",
    "answer": "'a'"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which method is used to format strings in Python?",
    "a": "add()",
    "b": "append()",
    "c": "concat()",
    "d": "format()",
    "answer": "format()"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which method is used to return a view of all keys in a dictionary?",
    "a": "my_dict.keys()",
    "b": "my_dict.values()",
    "c": "my_dict.items()",
    "d": "my_dict.all_keys()",
    "answer": "my_dict.keys()"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the data type used to represent whole numbers without decimals in Python?",
    "a": "Float",
    "b": "Boolean",
    "c": "String",
    "d": "Integer",
    "answer": "Integer"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given the Python code result = 10 + 20 * 30, what is the value of result?",
    "a": "900",
    "b": "610",
    "c": "300",
    "d": "600",
    "answer": "610"
  }
]